Finding Aid for Elmwood Cemetery (Detroit, Mich.) photographs, ca. 1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Elmwood Cemetery (Detroit, Mich.) photographs circa 1980
Elmwood Cemetery (Detroit, Mich.).
0.2 linear feet including 157 copyprints
91116 UBB.2 2
Photographs relating to Detroit and to Elmwood Cemetery in Detroit.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Mark C. Stevens (donor no. 7138 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Detroit, Michigan cemetery.
The collection consists of copyprints made from color slides taken by Mark C. Stevens, secretary-treasurer of Elmwood Cemetery. Included are views of Detroit, the neighborhood around the cemetery, scenery within the cemetery, and gravestones, monuments, and markers. The collection also includes a transcript of commentary made by Stevens on each of the photographs.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Cemeteries--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.); Elmwood Cemetery (Detroit, Mich.); Tombs and sepulchral monuments--Michigan--Detroit.
Contributors:
Stevens, Mark Chancellor.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Descriptive information
  - Item listing with index to the photographs (Folder 1)
  - Transcript of commentary by Mark C. Stevens on each photographs (Folder 1)
- Copy prints
  - Contemporary view of Detroit River with boats, [1] (Folder 2)
  - Contemporary view of Detroit River with Cobo Hall, [2] (Folder 2)
  - Contemporary view of Detroit River with "Unitramp" at Renaissance Center, [3] (Folder 2)
  - Contemporary view of Detroit River with Renaissance Center and Ford Auditorium, [4] (Folder 2)
  - View of Ford Auditorium from First Federal Savings and Loan Building, [5] (Folder 2)
  - Ruined house in neighborhood, front view, [6] (Folder 2)
  - Ruined house in neighborhood, side view, [7] (Folder 2)
  - Fire station near cemetery, [8] (Folder 2)
  - Calvary Baptist Church, [9] (Folder 2)
  - Huntington Place Sales Center, [10] (Folder 2)
  - Huntington Place under construction, [11] (Folder 2)
  - Elmwood Cemetery through fence, [12] (Folder 2)
  - Elmwood Cemetery marker stone, [13] (Folder 2)
  - View of street through fence and trees, [14] (Folder 2)
  - View of trees and gravestones, [15] (Folder 2)
  - Gatehouse and office, [16] (Folder 2)
  - Interior of office, [17] (Folder 2)
  - Historic site marker, [18] (Folder 2)
  - View of the valley of Parent's Creek (later Bloody Run), [19] (Folder 2)
  - Road along Bloody Run, [20] (Folder 2)
  - Monument of Halmor H. Emmons, [21] (Folder 2)
  - Chapel as restored after 1976, [22] (Folder 2)
  - Chapel, vandalized, distant view November 17, 1976, [23] (Folder 2)
  - Vandalized chapel, front view, [24] (Folder 2)
  - Vandalized chapel, from valley, [25] (Folder 2)
  - Restored chapel, angle view, [26] (Folder 2)
  - Restored outer wall with plaque 1856, [27] (Folder 2)
  - Plaque (replica) re. 1960 restoration, [28] (Folder 2)
  - Memorial to Renville Wheat, [29] (Folder 2)
  - Pews of cherry wood, [30] (Folder 2)
  - Altar, closeup with Pewabic vase, [31] (Folder 2)
  - Chapel interior looking toward altar, [32] (Folder 2)
  - Lectern, [33] (Folder 2)
  - Window opposite altar, [34] (Folder 2)
  - Cut-leaf maples, [35] (Folder 2)
  - Red maple near Weitzell monument, [36] (Folder 2)
  - Ginkgo Tree, [37] (Folder 2)
  - Chestnut and other trees at twilight, [38] (Folder 2)
  - Jacob Merritt Howard monument, [39] (Folder 2)
  - Valley at twilight, [40] (Folder 2)
  - "Butler's Allee" locusts, [41] (Folder 2)
  - View of cemetery of elm, juniper, and chestnut, [42] (Folder 2)
  - Upper valley, early autumn, [43] (Folder 2)
  - Oaks and maples under Indian summer sky, [44] (Folder 2)
  - Slope valley below Stroh lot, [45] (Folder 2)
  - Cut-leaf maple in fall, [46] (Folder 2)
  - Young hard maple in November, [47] (Folder 2)
  - Burning bush plant on valley floor, [48] (Folder 2)
  - View of large oak near Nall-Weaver, Dixon, and Pennycook lots with monuments of Keydel and Cullen Brown families, [49] (Folder 2)
  - View with monuments of Clippert and Pease families, [50] (Folder 2)
  - Samuel and Mary A. Crawford monument, [51] (Folder 3)
  - Hitching post, [52] (Folder 3)
  - Group plot of Civil War veterans, [53] (Folder 3)
  - Monument to Civil War veteran Henry Smith, [54] (Folder 3)
  - Firemen's cemetery lot, [55] (Folder 3)
  - Zinc plaque on Firemen's Monument showing old Firemen's Hall, [56] (Folder 3)
  - Monument in Strangers' Ground, to Rosa Lawson "Born in slavery", [57] (Folder 3)
  - Alvan Macaulay family monument by Marshall Fredericks, [58] (Folder 3)
  - Renville Wheat gravestone, [59] (Folder 3)
  - Merlin A. Cudlip family monument, [60] (Folder 3)
  - Lewis Cass monument, [61] (Folder 3)
  - Zachariah Chandler monument, [62] (Folder 3)
  - James McMillan and Grace McMillan Jarvis vaults in Hazel Dell, [63] (Folder 3)
  - Hammond family vault, [64] (Folder 3)
  - Wesson-Seyburn mausoleum, [65] (Folder 3)
  - Wesson-Seyburn mausoleum interior vaults, [66] (Folder 3)
  - John E. King mausoleum, [67] (Folder 3)
  - Traugott (TRAUGOTT) Schmidt mausoleum, [68] (Folder 3)
  - Florance D. Eatherly mausoleum, [69] (Folder 3)
  - George F. Moore mausoleum, [70] (Folder 3)
  - Thomas W. Palmer mausoleum, [71] (Folder 3)
  - Buhl family vault, [72] (Folder 3)
  - Alger mausoleum, [73] (Folder 3)
  - Caulkins family monument, [74] (Folder 3)
  - Augusta Willoughby chair monument, [75] (Folder 3)
  - Stephens family memorial, [76] (Folder 3)
  - James F. Joy family monument, [77] (Folder 3)
  - Chambe family monument, [78] (Folder 3)
  - Gravestone of Dr. John Linn Irwin, [79] (Folder 3)
  - Blain-Gray-Adair marker, front view, [80] (Folder 3)
  - Blain-Gray-Adair marker, back view, [81] (Folder 3)
  - Monument to Walter Harper and Nancy Martin, [82] (Folder 3)
  - Hiram Walker tombstone, [83] (Folder 3)
  - Truman Handy Newberry monument, [84] (Folder 3)
  - Oliver Newberry monument, [85] (Folder 3)
  - Remick monument and markers, [86] (Folder 3)
  - James D. Standish monument, [87] (Folder 3)
  - Rumney, Doughty and Russel monuments, [88] (Folder 3)
  - David Smart, DeGarmo Jones, and Hill monuments, [89] (Folder 3)
  - Lots at valley's edge in midsummer, [90] (Folder 3)
  - View from above valley of upper end, [91] (Folder 3)
  - Stroh family lot, [92] (Folder 3)
  - Gravestone of Philip Kling (1856-1857), [93] (Folder 3)
  - Augusta and Wilhelm Hartman stones, [94] (Folder 3)
  - Herman H. Freiwald gravestone, [95] (Folder 3)
  - Gravestone of infant, son of John & Elizabeth Desch, [96] (Folder 3)
  - Gravestone of Fritz Mau (1875-1890), [97] (Folder 3)
  - Gravestone of Mrs-August (Minnie) Franke, [98] (Folder 3)
  - Marker of Anna Rahn, (1865-1878), [99] (Folder 3)
  - Marker of Johanna E. Fritsche Hornbogen 1821-1883, [100] (Folder 3)
  - August Steller family monument, [101] (Folder 4)
  - Catherine Navarre Brevoort gravestone, [102] (Folder 4)
  - Henry B. Brevoort gravestone, [103] (Folder 4)
  - George deBaptiste (1816-1875) gravestone, also note re Elizabeth Dennison Forth, [104] (Folder 4)
  - D. Augustus Straker gravestone, [105] (Folder 4)
  - Henry Moy gravestone, [106] (Folder 4)
  - Wie Kim Lim gravestone, [107] (Folder 4)
  - Michael I. TOPALOU Gravestone, [109] (Folder 4)
  - Nadine P. Topalou (Comtesse Adeline Bon de Saint Hilaire) gravestone, [108] (Folder 4)
  - Count Cyril Tolstoi gravestone, [110] (Folder 4)
  - Lewis-Muir-Currie lot, [111] (Folder 4)
  - Stinchfield plot, [112] (Folder 4)
  - Christian Moll gravestones, [113] (Folder 4)
  - Gravestone of Judge Samuel Douglas (1814-1898), and Elizabeth Campbell Douglas, [114] (Folder 4)
  - Maire family monument-includes Edward and Frances Maire Bryant, [115] (Folder 4)
  - A new grave, [116] (Folder 4)
  - Gravestone of Henry Davis (1839-1842), [117] (Folder 4)
  - Solomon Sibley ledger stone, [118] (Folder 4)
  - Hiram Joy monument, [119] (Folder 4)
  - Rt. Rev. Thomas Frederick Davies monument, [120] (Folder 4)
  - James A. Abbott monument, [121] (Folder 4)
  - Pound family monument, [122] (Folder 4)
  - Brig. Gen. John Robertson gravestone, [123] (Folder 4)
  - William Wreford monument, [124] (Folder 4)
  - Winter view of Bloody Run, [125] (Folder 4)
  - Howard Graves Meredith lot, [126] (Folder 4)
  - Henry T. Thurber family plot, [127] (Folder 4)
  - Ellen Wells Russell gravestone, [128] (Folder 4)
  - Christmas wreath on monument, [129] (Folder 4)
  - "Little Minot" stone, [130] (Folder 4)
  - Charles E. Hilton stone, [131] (Folder 4)
  - Mark Buel Stevens stone, [132] (Folder 4)
    copy photo not available
  - Marcus Stevens children's marker (Stevens family monument), [133] (Folder 4)
  - Catherine Burnham Stevens marker (Stevens family monument), [134] (Folder 4)
  - Mark Burnham Stevens family monument, [135] (Folder 4)
  - Hiram Stevens monument, [136] (Folder 4)
  - Charles C. Trowbridge monument, [137] (Folder 4)
  - George F. Porter monument, [138] (Folder 4)
  - Elijah Brush monument, [139] (Folder 4)
  - Benjamin Vernor monument, [140] (Folder 4)
  - Howard Graves Meredith lot during a snow, [141] (Folder 4)
  - Charles Larned and-Mary Larned Howard monument, [142] (Folder 4)
  - Gen. Alpheus Williams memorial, [143] (Folder 4)
  - Stark gravestone, [144] (Folder 4)
  - George Washington Stark marker, [145] (Folder 4)
  - John C. Lodge marker, [146] (Folder 4)
  - Douglass Houghton marker, [147] (Folder 4)
  - Waterman monument by Randolph Rogers on Turner lot, [148] (Folder 4)
  - Eben Beach family monument, [149] (Folder 4)
  - W. R. Candler monument, [150] (Folder 4)
  - View in early summer, [151] (Folder 4)
  - View in early autumn, [152] (Folder 4)
  - Eber Brock Ward monument, [153] (Folder 4)
  - View with funeral tent, [154] (Folder 4)
  - McMillan, Hugh, [155] (Folder 4)
  - Lodge Monument, [156] (Folder 4)
  - Unidentified building, [157] (Folder 4)